<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<content group="users" ident="users/support" nname="Support"
	publish="yes" toRoot="../"
	lastchanged="$Date$ by $Author$">
	<column id="content">
		<h1>Getting support</h1>
		<h2>Mailing list</h2>
		<p>
			We generally recommend the use of the mailing list maltcms-user for
			novice users of Maltcms, ChromA and ChromAUI. This is the place to
			get in contact with the
			developers
			quickly and ask questions on just
			about everything. You can subscribe to the mailing list
			<a href="https://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/maltcms-user"
				target="_blank">here</a>
			or post a message anonymously, which will then be published at the
			list moderator's discretion. If you discover bugs and are not sure on
			how to report them, we would also recommend to post your
			findings on the list, so that we can create a bug tracker item for you.
		</p>
		<h2>Bug reporting</h2>
		<p>
			If you happen to stumble across bugs in Maltcms or any associated
			application, we would appreciate your feedback.
			We provide a publicly accessible
			<a href="https://sourceforge.net/tracker/?group_id=251287&amp;atid=1126545" target="_blank">issue tracker</a>, which does not require
			you to have an account at sourceforge. However, in order to be able to
			contact you, we recommend to register an account with sourceforge, or
			register on
			the mailing list, where you can also submit a bug report directly. These
			will then be transferred to our Trac instance issue tracking system.
		</p>
		<h2>Trac issue tracking</h2>
		<p>
			Software may contain bugs, which are typically hard to spot by the
			persons writing the software. Although we test Maltcms regularly, it
			may fail for certain operations, file types or the like. We thus
			provide means to get help fast from the people developing Maltcms.
			For advanced users and developers, the first place to turn to is the
			<a href="http://sourceforge.net/apps/trac/maltcms/" title="Trac issue tracking system"
				target="_blank">Trac</a>
			instance on sourceforge, which
			allows you to view existing
			<em>tickets</em>
			, e.g. reports of known bugs, requests for enhancement and so on.
			However, in order to be able to create new tickets, you will need to
			get an
			<a href="https://sourceforge.net/account/registration/">account with
				sourceforge</a>
			in order to avoid spam.
		</p>
	</column>
</content>
