<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>Programmatic Creation of a Workflow</title>
        <author>Nils Hoffmann</author>
        <date>Nov. 8th, 2011</date>
    </properties>

  <!-- Optional HEAD element, which is copied as is into the XHTML <head> element -->
    <head>
        <script src="http://yandex.st/highlightjs/6.1/highlight.min.js"></script>
        <link rel="stylesheet" href="http://yandex.st/highlightjs/6.1/styles/default.min.css"/>
    </head>
    <body>

    <!-- The body of the document contains a number of sections -->
        <section name="About Maltcms and ChromA">
            <subsection name="What is Maltcms?">
                <p>
			Maltcms, short for "Modular Application Toolkit for Chromatography Mass-Spectrometry" is an application framework 
			mainly suited for developers working in the domain of bioinformatics for metabolomics and proteomics. Its aim is to 
			provide reusable, efficient datastructures, abstracting from the various low-level data-formats like netcdf (ANDIMS), mzXML, mzData and mzML
			and providing consistent access to data features like mass spectra, chromatograms and metadata. Furthermore, Maltcms provides a platform 
			for the implementation and execution of processing pipelines. New and existing algorithms can be easily implemented or included and executed together with 
			existing processing elements.   
                </p>
                <p>For a more extensive list of features, please refer to the 
                    <a href="users/features.html">features</a> section.
                </p>
            </subsection>	
            <subsection name="What is ChromA/ChromA4D?">
                <p>
			ChromA and ChromA4D are particular pipelines of defined processing elements, which realize the typical workflow of GC-MS/LC-MS (ChromA) and 
			GCxGC-MS (ChromA4D) data analysis.
                </p>
            </subsection>	
        </section>
        <section name="Future Developments">
            <p>We are currently developing a rich client application, called ChromAUI, which is based on the Netbeans RCP framework.
		The aim of this RCP application is, to allow manual interaction with the data, as well as visualization of raw and processed data. However, 
		it will also be possible to define custom processing pipelines, run them as batch tasks and inspect the results, while they are being created.
		If you are interested to try ChromAUI, please go to 
                <a href="info/contact.html">contact</a>.
            </p>
            <p>
		An early preview and some screenshots of ChromAUI are now featured on 
                <a href="http://blogs.sun.com/geertjan/entry/metabolomics_and_proteomics_on_the">Geertjan Wielenga's blog</a>.
            </p>
        </section>
        <hr/>
        <section name="News">
            <subsection name="ChromAUI at the Perspektive 2010 Science Fair">
                <p>On Thursday, November 11th, we will have a poster presentation at the science fair of the general purpose job fair Perspektive at Bielefeld University. Have a look at it 
                    <a href="http://www.cebitec.uni-bielefeld.de/~hoffmann">here</a>.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Netbeans RCP Training at Bielefeld University">
                <p>Geertjan Wielenga and Aljoscha Rittner recently gave a great three day introductory course on core Netbeans RCP technologies to a group of twenty people at Bielefeld University. During the course, Geertjan asked for presentations of existing applications based on Netbeans RCP, 
                    <a href="http://netbeans.dzone.com/video-bioinformatics-research" title="ChromAUI Video">and here it is</a>.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="ChromAUI featured as a Netbeans RCP application">
                <p>After a recent inquiry about our project ChromAUI from Geertjan Wielenga, I prepared a few screenshots of the current prototype and wrote short descriptions for them.
		Visit 
                    <a href="http://blogs.sun.com/geertjan/entry/metabolomics_and_proteomics_on_the">Geertjan Wielenga's blog</a> to see for yourself.
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
